Ananthu A

Fleet Manager

Summary

Vigilant Vehicle Fleet Manager with the ability to manage and maintain fleets in multiple locations. Adept at implementing security procedures and identifying safety risks. Focused on applying operational knowledge of vehicle maintenance, problem solving, and adhering to industry regulations. Around 11 years Experience in Fleet Management.

Education

Diploma in Mechanical Enggineering / March, 2010 - April, 2012

Rajasthan university

Skiltech - India

80%

Plus Two: Humanities / March, 2008 - March, 2009

Mahatma Gandhi University

EMGHSS Veli Kochi

75%

Work Experience

Automobile Mechanic / March, 2012 - March, 2018

Geeyem Motors

Delegated jobs to subordinates and monitored quality of work. Completed customer orders and warranty services according to manufacturer specifications.

Eranakulam, India

All Kerala Fleet Head / April, 2018 - September, 2020

Cms info system Itd

- Vigilant Vehicle Fleet Head with the ability to manage workshops
- maintain and supervise fleets in multiple locations.
- Adapt at implementing security procedures and identifying safety risks
- Focused on applying operational knowledge of vehicle maintenance and handling problem solving by adhering to industry regulations.
- Manage 150 vehicle fleet.
- Maintain great relations with Vendor Ensure smooth operations.
- Cost management and control.
- Technical Knowledge.
- Managed employee scheduling, payroll and data collection to maximize project
- Suggested actionable improvements to increase efficiency and reduce expenses.

Eranakulam, India



Profile Information



Ananthureshma04@gmail.co



+919746409993



4/1156 North Cherlai Mattancherry Kochi-682002 Eranakulam

Skills

PROBLEM SOLVING

FUEL MANAGEMENT

OPERATIONS & TEAM HANDLING

RISK MANAGEMENT

AUDITING

DECISION MAKING

GPS MONITORING

TRANSPORTATION

DOCUMENTATION & MIS

NEGOTIATION SKIL

VENDOR MANAGEMENT

DEVELOP AND MAINTAIN ACCURATE RECORDS OF FLEET OPERATIONS

Fleet Head / October, 2020 - November, 2021

SecureValue India Itd

- Pragmatic Operations Head with hands on experience of handling end to end supply chain and logistics operations.
- Specializes in operations planning, implementation and process streamlining.
- Believes in leading from the front and team building to achieve organizational goals and also develop the skills of team members.
- Managed team of employees, overseeing hiring, training and professional growth of employees.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to complete projects on time.
- Created spreadsheets using Microsoft Excel for daily, weekly and monthly reporting.

Eranakulam, India

Fleet Manager / December, 2021 - July, 2022

Owleto Technologies pt Itd

- Across various domains like Analytics, Operation, Supply chain management, Planning, Logistics and maintaining.
- Team Handling & Fleet plan & Monitoring operation.
- Highly motivated, Pro-active and possess good presentation, interpersonal & problem solving skills.
- Generated daily reports detailing suggested process improvement initiatives to inform management.
- Completed projects by effectively delegating tasks and overseeing employee performance.
- Suggested actionable improvements to increase efficiency and reduce expenses.
- Trained drivers to manage time effectively, improving overall mileage performance.
- Provided all drivers with pertinent safety materials regarding rules and regulations.
- Documented equipment transfers and sales details for accurate record keeping.
- Supervised maintenance team and effectively delegated assignments to optimize processes.

Calicut, India

Fleet Operators Manager (RTO &OPS)/ August, 2022 - present,

Dilip Buildcon Ltd

- · Documented equipment transfers and sales details for accurate record keeping.
- Supervised maintenance team and effectively delegated assignments to optimize processes.
- Conducted regular field audits for better performance.
- Prepared for highway patrol investigations by collaborating with various departments and examining potential risks.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Introduced incentivization programs to increase employee performances}.$
- Generated daily reports detailing suggested process improvement initiatives to inform management.
- Maintained accurate driver information for delivery scheduling.
- Develop and maintain accurate records of fleet operations, including vehicle history, maintenance, and repairs, and associated costs.
- Trained drivers to manage time effectively, improving overall mileage performance.
- Handling Vehicles Documentation & Vehicle Condition Daily Basis.
- Monitor and analyse costs associated with the fleet, including fuel consumption, maintenance, repairs, and tyres, and identify opportunities for cost savings.
- •Negotiate contracts and manage relationships with vendors, such as repair shops.

Villupuram, Chennai

MONITORING VEHICLE CONDITION

MONITOR VEHICLE USAGE AND PERFORMANCE

CONDUCTING DRIVERS TRAINING & SAFETY CLASS

MANAGING THE FLEET COST

Languages

ENGLISH: Expert

HINDI: Fluent

TAMIL: Fluent

MALAYALAM: Expert